geappliances.com 2011-12-07

# GE Appliances Privacy Policy

##### Privacy Statement   
Last Updated November 8, 2011 

#### Information We Collect and How We Use It

##### Personal Information 

You may choose to provide personal information (such as your name, address, phone number and email address) on this web site. Here are some of the ways you may provide the information and the types of information you may submit. We also tell you how we may use the information. Some of the features listed below may not be present on the website from which you have accessed this Privacy Statement.

> ##### Contact Us 
> 
> If you email us through the "Contact Us" link on this site, we may ask for information such as your name, phone number, country, zip code and email address so we can respond to your questions and comments. You may choose to provide additional information as well, such as your postal address or fax number.
> 
> ##### e-Newsletters 
> 
> If you would like to receive our e-Newsletters, we may ask for your name and email address so we can send you our e-Newsletters and communicate with you.
> 
> ##### Buying Guides 
> 
> On some of our web sites, if you would like to receive buying guides that include buying tips, special offers and information on products, we ask for your name and email address so we can send you the buying guides and other communications.
> 
> ##### Questionnaires and Surveys 
> 
> We occasionally may ask visitors to our web site or consumers registering a product with us to participate in surveys or opinion polls about their experience, activities, attitudes and interests. These surveys help us serve you better and improve the usefulness of our site and our products. In conducting these surveys we may ask you for information such as your name and email address. We do not keep any personal information about you in connection with your participation in a survey unless you specifically agree to provide that information.
> 
> ##### Send Ads, Videos and GE Appliances Pages to a Friend 
> 
> On some of our web sites you can send certain GE TV and picture ads, appliances videos and GE appliances pages to your friends. To do so, we ask you to provide your name and your friend's email address. We also may ask for your email address. By providing another person's contact information to us, you acknowledge that you have obtained appropriate consent to provide this information and to have this individual receive the information you have asked us to send. We use this information to send the ads, videos and pages to your friends and to communicate with you. We will not use information you provide about other people for any purpose except the purpose you direct without first getting their consent. 
> 
> ##### Parts and Accessories and Extended Warranty Orders 
> 
> If you purchase parts and accessories or extended warranties through our site, we ask for your contact information, including your name, postal address, phone number and email address and your payment information, including your credit card number and billing and shipping information. We ask for this information so we can confirm and process your order, provide you with updates on your order, process any returns, contact you concerning your order, and otherwise communicate with you. 
> 
> ##### Locating a Dealer 
> 
> On some of our web sites, if you would like to locate a dealer, we ask for your zip code. If you would like directions to a local dealer, we ask for your physical address. You may also choose to provide your email address when locating a dealer through our site. We use this information to provide the contact information for and directions to a dealer.
> 
> ##### Buying Appliances
> 
> If you would like to buy a GE appliance, we ask for your zip code so we can direct you to the web site of a GE authorized dealer.
> 
> ##### Appliance Service 
> 
> On some of our web sites, if you would like to schedule appliance services, re-schedule or check the status of your service request, we ask for contact information such as your name, phone number, postal address and email address so we may contact you regarding your request. If you inquire only about service pricing information, we ask for your zip code so we may provide you with a service cost estimate based on your location.
> 
> ##### Register Your Appliance 
> 
> On some of our web sites, you may register appliances. We ask you for information such as your name, postal address, email address and phone number. We use this information to register your product and provide repair services within the provisions of your warranty and our service contract obligations. We also may use your email address to notify you about special offers, subscribe you to our e-newsletters and provide information about our products. By registering an appliance online, you may be automatically entered into a sweepstakes and your information will be used to contact you if you are selected as a winner.
> 
> ##### Sweepstakes 
> 
> If you would like to enter our sweepstakes, we ask for information such as your name, email address, postal address and phone number so that we can enter you in the sweepstakes. You will also be contacted if you are selected as a winner. We also may use your email address to communicate with you, such as to contact you about special promotions, discounts, updates and new products.
> 
> ##### Recipes Communities 
> 
> On some of our web sites you may join a recipe community. We may ask for information such as your email address. We use this information to provide you with access to the community and to communicate with you. 
> 
> ##### Discounts to Non-Profit Agencies 
> 
> We offer special discounts to non-profit agencies. If you would like to apply for a discount, we ask for information such as your name, postal address, email address and phone number. We use this information to process your application and to communicate with you. 
> 
> ##### Rebates 
> 
> If you would like us to process or communicate with you in connection with rebates and special offers, we may ask for information such as your name, postal address and phone number or we may ask you to download and application so that we can respond to your request and communicate with you.
> 
> ##### Online Chat
> 
> You may choose to participate in an online web chat with a GE associate. We will conduct the session based on information you provide during that request. Historical information, **which includes name and email address** may be retained by us to assist you in any subsequent online web chat and for internal review and training.
> 
> ##### Other Website Features 
> 
> We offer visitors various features for their information and enjoyment, which we may change from time to time. We may ask you to submit certain personal information so we can provide you with these features.
> 
> ##### Other Ways We May Use Your Information 
> 
> We may use personal information you submit to enhance your experience with the GE family of companies. We also may use the information you provide for internal purposes. These purposes include administration of our websites, data analytics and compliance with law or legal process and our policies and procedures.

##### Non Personal Information 

We may collect certain aggregate and non personal information when you visit this web site. Aggregate and non personal information does not relate to a single identifiable visitor. It tells us such things as how many users visited our site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our web site to our visitors. We collect this information either through "cookie" technology or with "web beacons", as explained below.

> ##### Cookies 
> 
> Like many companies, we may use browser cookies on this web site. Browser cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain web sites. We use browser cookies to tell us, for example, whether you've visited us before or if you're a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Browser cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.
> 
> The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new browser cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new browser cookie, and how to disable existing browser cookies. Remember though, without browser cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our web site features.
> 
> We also may use flash cookies on our web site to enhance your online experience. Flash cookies are similar to browser cookies, except that they can store data more complex than simple text. Flash cookies, by themselves, cannot do anything to or with the data on your computer. In addition, flash cookies cannot access or remember your email address or other personal information unless you provide the information on this site. We may use flash cookies to provide you with a better user experience. You can manage and disable flash cookies by clicking here for Manage and Disable Flash Cookies.
> 
> ##### Web Beacons 
> 
> Certain pages on our site contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party. We use log files to store the data that is collected through web beacons.
> 
> We may use third party web beacons to help manage online advertising. These web beacons are provided by our ad management partner. Web Beacons enable our ad management partner to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our web site. The cookie on your web browser was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with our ad management partner. With both cookies and web beacon technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, postal address, phone number, or email address. 
> 
> ##### Third Party Advertising and Links to Other Web Sites
> 
> We may work with third parties to serve our ads on other web sites as well as our web site. Some of these ads contain cookies and/or web beacons that are used to track user behavior. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies or web beacons set by third parties. We do not have control over, or access to, the information contained in these third party cookies or web beacons. For more information about these specialized cookies and other technologies, and how to "OPT OUT" of information collection by these companies, we suggest you visit <http://networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>. 

#### Information We Share 

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about our web site visitors, except as described here. We may share personal information you provide within the GE family of companies and with third parties that may offer you products or services we believe may interest you. We also may share personal information provided by web site visitors with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. For example, we may share personal information you provide with third parties who assist us in: product delivery and installation; warranty or service contract claims clearinghouse; call center operations, parts delivery, repair service, product recall; order processing; billing; payments processing; processing and mailing rebates; offering promotions, discounts, and/or products; quality of product or service surveys; data modeling for marketing analysis; and product or service offerings. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. 

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided through this web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

#### Information We Transfer 

We may transfer the personal information we collect on this site to other countries where we do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described here unless otherwise required by applicable laws.

#### Links to Other Sites 

We provide links to other web sites for your convenience and information. These sites may have their own privacy statements in place, which we recommend you review if you visit any linked web sites. We are not responsible for the content of linked sites or any use of the sites.

#### Children's Privacy 

This web site is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the site. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on the site, we will delete the information from our records. 

#### How We Protect Personal Information 

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of the personal information you provide on this web site. 

#### Your Choices 

When you visit certain parts of our site, such as when you register an appliance, order a buying guide, obtain local dealer information, order a part or accessory, shop for a warranty, schedule service, or email a GE appliances ad, page, or video to a friend, you may update your privacy preferences by clicking the "Set my email preferences" link. 

#### Updates to Our Privacy Statement 

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will post a prominent notice on this web site to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Statement and indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated.

#### How to Contact Us 

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us.

> **Appliances (including parts & service)**   
> 800-626-2005   
>  http://www.geappliances.com/service_and_support/contact/

> **Home Energy Management**   
>  _Nucleus, Energy Display, Thermostat and appliances with Brillion™ technology_   
> 800-220-6899   
>  http://www.geappliances.com/home-energy-manager/contact-us.htm

**As always, with your continued use of the website, you may update your privacy choices at any time at "Set My Email Preferences"**

In addition to the above Privacy Statement, if you use a GE Appliances mobile application, the below GE Mobile Privacy Policy shall also apply.

#### Mobile Privacy Policy

#### Mobile Information We Collect

Personally identifiable information (e.g. Name, email address) we collect consists only of what you share with us. For example, certain products may ask for this type of information so that we may contact you by phone or email at your request. You choose what, how, and when you want to share.

If you use any location-enabled products, you may be sending us location information. GE does not store or use this information other than to provide the service you requested. For example, a mobile product may use GPS data to find a nearby restaurant you requested. Location-enabled features are opt-in and you have control over your participation and can turn these services off at any time.

Web-enabled mobile applications may use cookies or web beacons and other methods to customize your browsing experience. Please see the above GE Appliances Privacy Statement for more information. Some mobile applications will utilize Google Analytics (or similar tool) to help us better serve our customers through improved products, services, and revisions to the mobile applications. This collected information will not identify you to GE. It may, however, let us know anonymously, which services and features you are using the most within the application, as well as device type and hardware features, country and language of download.

Use of 3rd party services such as social sharing sites (e.g., Facebook & Twitter) is governed by the privacy practices of those services. GE does not capture or store your login information or other personally identifiable information for these services, however session info or cookies may be stored.

#### Mobile How We Use Collected Information

We use the information to personalize your experience with the application and to improve your overall experience including the development of new products, services, and features. We also use the information to provide customer support, and when applicable, register and administer your account. Additionally, we may use the information you provide to contact you about updates to our service.

Information you provide may be used to fulfill the service(s) or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized. For example, if you authorize a purchase through a mobile eCommerce application, we will use provided information to ship and bill you.

#### Mobile Information sharing

GE does not share any collected information with 3rd parties with the following exceptions: 

  * GE may provide some personal data to third-party partners that are providing services essential to your mobile user experience.
  * All requests are sent through your mobile carrier's network and your carrier may have access to it. Consult your carrier's privacy policies for additional information.
  * Certain mobile products and services and manufacturers allow you to interact and share your information with others. For example, you may want to Tweet or post to your Facebook page content from a GE mobile application. Consult your mobile device manufacturer, or mobile product or application developer's privacy policies for additional information.
